Guide to the Lucy Ann Geiselman collection, 1992-1996 MVC0014.MS
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Lucy Ann Geiselman collection
1992-1996
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MVC0014.MS
1 Linear Feet 2 document boxes
This collection contains appointment books, personal notes, and administrative files belonging to Lucy Ann Geiselman. The materials range in date from 1992-1996.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection is from Mount Vernon College, which The George Washington University acquired in 1999.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains inaguration photographs, correpondence, notebooks, and other administrative files belonging to Lucy Ann Geiselman. The materials range in date from 1992-1996.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Lucy Ann Geiselman was named the eighth president of Mount Vernon College in 1992. She served as president until 1996. The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999.
Geiselman was serving as president when Mount Vernon originally merged with GW in 1996.
Women's colleges; Women -- Education; Mount Vernon College
- AAC "Connections"--"Mount Vernon Bets Future on Partnership with Georgetown", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Appointment book, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Appointment book, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Appointment book, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Appointment book, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clippings from the Washington Post, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Inaguration photos and negatives, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Invitations and programs to Lucy Ann Geiselman's inaguration, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lucy Ann Geiselman photographs, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Middle East, Kuwait, Bahrain trip, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Middle East, Kuwait, Bahrain trip photos, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mount Vernon College Bulletin, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Notebook--Communication on Trustees, Executive Committee and Full Board Meeting, April 27-29, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Steno notebooks, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Telephone messages book, circa 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Webb building and the "University of Chicago Record", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)